A Guide to the G. Grahame Duce Papers 1920-1947
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
G. Grahame Duce Papers 1920-1947
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-005
1 container; 0.2 cu. ft.
Papers of president of Duce Aeronautical Research (Baltimore, Maryland). Includes typescript "Alphabetical Index of Approved Aircraft"; manuscript drafts of articles on pilot safety, paratroop devices, air races, Boeing XB-47 Stratojet, the future of jet pilots; and miscellaneous notes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The G. Grahame Duce Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1987.
Biographical/Historical Information
G. Grahame Duce was President of Duce Aeronautical Research, located at 2100 Mount Royal Ter. Apt. 6, Baltimore 17, Maryland.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the papers of G. Grahame Duce, President of Duce Aeronautical Research in Baltimore, Maryland. Included within the collection are various airplane notes and characteristics from 1920 to 1939, an approved aircraft index from 1947, and manuscript drafts of articles, some from 1947, discussing new paratroop devices, the fastest long-ranger, the Martin XB-48, the building of XB-48, airlines in the red, pilot judgment, air races, the Boeing XB-47, the jet pilot, and the future of jet planes.
Arrangement
The papers are divided into twelve folders and are arranged in a roughly chronological order.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Businesspeople; Science and Technology
Contents List
- Various notes 1920-1939 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Manuscript drafts of articles 1942-1945 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Index of aircraft Jul-Sep 1947 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Manuscript drafts of articles Jul 1947 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Manuscript drafts of articles Jul 1947 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Manuscript drafts of articles Jul 1947 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Manuscript drafts of articles 1947 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Manuscript drafts of articles n.d. (Box-folder 1-8)
- Manuscript drafts of articles n.d. (Box-folder 1-9)
- Manuscript drafts of articles n.d. (Box-folder 1-10)
- Manuscript drafts of articles n.d. (Box-folder 1-11)
- Manuscript drafts of articles n.d. (Box-folder 1-12)